Fisseha Berhane, Ph.D. Candidate 443-970-2353 fisseha@jhu.edu

More than six years of data intensive research experience using R, Python, Matlab and GIS. Strong academic training and extensive experience with data mining and machine learning methods. Developed a rainfall prediction app that uses various prediction models for any geographic location with Shiny, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Data Science enthusiast. In addition to the data science courses I have done in grad school, I have taken more than 15 edx, coursera and Udacity data science courses with R, Spark, Python and Matlab. Have done various data science related projects. Please visit my website for details on the projects I have worked on, data science related courses I have taken in grad school, online data science certifications and more.

Education

Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD --- Ph.D in Atmospheric Physics Aug. 2015 (expected)

Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD ---- M.A. in Atmospheric Physics May 2013

University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT --------M.S. in Hydro-climatology May 2011

Mekelle University, Ethiopia ------------------B.Sc. in Civil Engineering June 2006

Research Positions

Graduate Research Assistant, Department of Earth and Planetary Science, Johns Hopkins University,
Baltimore, Maryland.

August 2011 – 2015

Graduate Research Assistant, Department of Natural Resources and the Environment, University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT 2009 – May 2011

Teaching Experience

Teaching assistant (TA), Department of Earth and Planetary Science, The Johns Hopkins University,
Baltimore, Maryland. Spring 2013

Assistant Lecturer, Department of Civil Engineering, Mekelle University, Ethiopia 2006-2009

Publications

Three peer-reviewed publications in the Journal of Climate (JCL), which is among the most prestigious Journals in Atmospheric Science, one in preparation and master's thesis.

Presentations

More than 12 presentations, including in prestigious international conferences such as American Geophysical Union (AGU) and American Meteorological Society (AMS).